uplabs.com 2016-06-23

# MaterialUp Privacy Policy – UpLabs

  * ## TYPES OF DATA COLLECTED

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage data and Email address. Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.

The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application.

Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.

Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services. Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

* * *

## MODE AND PLACE OF PROCESSING THE DATA

  * #### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data. 

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. 

  * #### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller. 

  * #### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data. 

  * #### The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Registration and authentication, Contacting the User and Content commenting.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

* * *

## DETAILED INFORMATION ON THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services: 

  * #### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior. This Application uses an internal analytics system that does not involve third parties.  
_Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data._

  * #### Mailing List or Newsletter 

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Application. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Application or after making a purchase.  
_Personal Data collected: Email address._

  * #### Content commenting

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of this Application. Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments. If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when users do not use the content commenting service. This Application has its own internal content comment system.  
_Personal Data collected: Usage data._

  * #### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow this Application to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, this Application will be able to access some Data, stored by these third party services, for registration or identification purposes.

Uplabs uses Twitter OAuth (Twitter, Inc.) to authenticate you as a User. Twitter OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Twitter, Inc. and is connected to the Twitter social network.  
_Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service._

  * #### Responsibility of Services and website Visitors.

Uplabs has not reviewed, and cannot review, all of the Content (graphics or text) posted to the Services, and cannot therefore be responsible for that content, use or effects. By operating the Services, Uplabs does not represent or imply that it endorses the Content there posted, or that it believes such material to be accurate, useful or non-harmful. You are responsible for taking precautions as necessary to protect yourself and your computer systems from viruses, worms, Trojan horses, and other harmful or destructive content. The Services may contain content that is offensive, indecent, or otherwise objectionable, as well as content containing technical inaccuracies, typographical mistakes, and other errors. The Services may also contain material that violates the privacy or publicity rights, or infringes the intellectual property and other proprietary rights, of third parties, or the downloading, copying or use of which is subject to additional terms and conditions, stated or unstated. Uplabs disclaims any responsibility for any harm resulting from the use by visitors of the Services and website, or from any downloading by those visitors of content there posted.

  * #### Links to Third-Party Web Site

Uplabs may provide hyperlinks to third-party web sites as a convenience to users of the Web Site or for advertising purposes. Uplabs does not control third-party web sites and is not responsible for the contents of any linked-to, third-party web sites or any hyperlink in a linked-to web site. Uplabs does not endorse, recommend or approve any third-party web site hyperlinked from the Web Site. Uplabs will have no liability to any entity for the content or use of the content available through such hyperlink. We do not endorse or hold ourselves responsible for the privacy policies or information gathering practices of any other Services, other than sites run by us. You understand that the information and opinions in the third party content represent solely the thoughts of the author and is neither endorsed by nor does it necessarily reflect our belief. 

* * *

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ABOUT DATA COLLECTION AND PROCESSING

  * #### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services. The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

  * #### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

  * #### The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to matt@uplabs.com

  * #### This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.

To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

  * #### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller removes the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

* * *

##  DEFINITIONS 

  * #### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

  * #### Usage Data

Information collected automatically from this Application (or third party services employed in this Application), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment. 

  * #### User

The individual using this Application, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refer. 

  * #### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers. 

  * #### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy. 

  * #### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application. 

  * #### This Application

The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

  * #### Cookie

Small piece of data stored in the User's device.

* * *

## Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies. This privacy policy relates solely to this Application.
